{
    "id": "54df69a2f2b7418da89a8832f79c654a",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "It's time you ........................... that stereo repaired.",
            "description": "A simple past is used after it's time to refer to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "get",
                "got",
                "had got"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0938ddb70dcf4469ab3b265467e0aa5d"
        },
        {
            "question": "She acts .......................... she knows his secrets.",
            "description": "Either could be used to say what a situation seems like.",
            "answers": [
                "as if",
                "as though",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "5d902355de4943a1b46eb5171578a2ce"
        },
        {
            "question": "It is time she ............................. a job.",
            "description": "A simple past is used after it's time to refer to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "finds",
                "found",
                "has found"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d7fdb5a632ba4638afff9f2a69d116c7"
        },
        {
            "question": "I wish I ............................. longer hair.",
            "description": "A simple past is used after I wish to express regret about the present.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "have had"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e9da4157823a43c9bf9f484b4b2de62e"
        },
        {
            "question": "It seems ..................................... the cat was injured in the fall.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "as if",
                "as though",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "32368a597afc4f6cac8fc711310e2ee2"
        },
        {
            "question": "It is high time she .............................. smoking.",
            "description": "A simple past is used after it is high time to refer to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "gives up",
                "gave up",
                "give up"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d17707be66f7448cb66a866bc6ecd415"
        },
        {
            "question": "It would have been better if you ............................... a doctor.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "consult",
                "consulted",
                "had consulted"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "68a55292dc424507928bd796cc965617"
        },
        {
            "question": "It would be better if you .................................. the police.",
            "description": "In type  2 conditional, we use a simple past in the if-clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "inform",
                "informed",
                "had informed"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bc30fed42469484f89761e4ccc35d4fd"
        },
        {
            "question": "I prefer classical music ............................... heavy metal.",
            "description": "We prefer x to y.",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "than",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "395716d349e64fa482aa5b3229ac9c78"
        },
        {
            "question": "I .............................. wait than leave.",
            "description": "Prefer is followed by a to-infinitive or gerund. Would rather is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "prefer",
                "rather",
                "would rather"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "cd72d3734a4f40b6bce6496f1b118518"
        },
        {
            "question": "I prefer calling my friends ................................. writing to them.",
            "description": "Prefer + ing form/to-infinitive + object + rather than + infinitive/ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "than",
                "rather than"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "1f116b23bb504c65bd178da95ffebdd0"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ................................. riding to driving.",
            "description": "Prefer can be followed by an ing form or  to-infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "would rather",
                "prefer",
                "rather"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bdb499527b0a460da792cc3cb4e66bb2"
        }
    ]
}